A Guide to the John C. Watkins Papers 1979-1999
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
John C. Watkins Papers 1979-1999
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 300
134.4 linear feet
John C. Watkins
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated to Special Collections and Archives by John C. Watkins in December 1992. Additional materials were donated in 1998, 1999 and 2002.
Biographical/Historical Information
John C. Watkins was born in Petersburg, Virginia, on March 1, 1947. He is the son of B. Chewning and Margaret Bowman Watkins. He attended Chesterfield County Schools and graduated from Midlothian High School in 1965. In 1969, he received a B.S. in Agriculture/Horticulture from Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Watkins served in the United States Army from 1969 through 1971. He has been affiliated with Watkins Nurseries, Inc. since 1971, and has served as president of the company since 1990. From 1973 to 1981, Watkins was an adjunct faculty member of J. Sargeant Reynolds Community College. He has served on the Chippenham Medical Center/Johnston-Willis Hospital Board of Directors (1993-present) and the Richmond Metro Electric Vehicle Readiness Committee as General Chairman (1996-present).
In 1982, Watkins was elected to the Virginia General Assembly-House of Delegates from the 34th Legislative District (Chesterfield, Powhatan, and Colonial Heights.) From 1983 to 1997, Watkins represented the 65th Legislative District (Chesterfield and Powhatan Counties). In 1998, Watkins was elected to the Virginia Senate where he represents the 10th Senatorial District comprised of the County of Powhatan and parts Chesterfield, Henrico, and the City of Richmond. Watkins has been active in encouraging increased cooperation between the City of Richmond, and the county governments of Henrico and Chesterfield.
He is married to Kathryn Clawson Watkins and has three children: John Michael, Robert Schofield, and Thomas Ryan.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains the office files of Senator John C. Watkins (1947- ) covering the years from 1979 through 2001 and includes correspondence, reports, memoranda, files on legislation and various topics and issues that the Virginia General Assembly addressed during this time period.
The correspondence contains letters to and from Senator Watkins and includes constituent requests for favors or patronage and letters of inquiry about legislation. Correspondents include: United States Senators Paul Trible and John Warner, Virginia Governors George Allen, Gerald Baliles, Thomas Bliley, James Gilmore III, Charles Robb, and L. Douglas Wilder III, and President of the United States George Bush.
The legislation covers issues of importance to Senator Watkins. Of particular concern are those that represent his committee assignments, including Agriculture, Conservation and National Resources, Commerce and Labor, Local Government, and Transportation. The Powhite Parkway, the Lottery, Health Care, Gun Control, Education, and Disney America are among some of the issues addressed in the collection. Watkins has been active in encouraging increased cooperation between the City of Richmond, and the county governments of Henrico and Chesterfield and the collection includes materials covering those issues.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically and chronological therein.
Organization
The collection is divided into four main sections - each representing a different donation of office files. The processed collection uses the file folder names created in Watkins' office.
Series I--Office Files (1979-1991)
Series II--Office Files (1984-1997)
Series III--Office Files (n.d., 1977-1999) [The bulk of the collection in this series dates from the late 1980s through the 1990s]
Series IV--Office File (n.d., 1997-2001)
Contents List
- Series I-Office files 1979-1980
  - Education Annual Reports 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Health (Vital Statistics) 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Marine Resources Commission Annual Report 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Minority Business Enterprises Annual Report 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Tayloe Murphy Institute 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Transportation Services for Human Resources 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol Safety Program Annual Report 1981 (Box 2)
  - Cumulative Index 1981 (Box 2)
  - Employee Relations Counselors Annual Report 1981 (Box 2)
  - Savings and Loans/Banking 1981 (Box 2)
  - Transportation--Plan (Central Shenandoah) 1981 (Box 2)
  - Transportation Study Final Report (Piedmont) 1981 (Box 2)
  - VDH and T-Critical Improvement Program 1981 (Box 2)
  - Virginia Tech Annual Report 1981 (Box 2)
  - Water Legislation Reports 1981 (Box 2)
  - Abortion Funding HB 541-542 1982 (Box 3)
  - Agriculture 1982 (Box 3)
  - Alcohol Programs HB 716, 721 1982 (Box 3)
  - American Institute of Architects 1982 (Box 3)
  - Appointments, Judicial 1982 (Box 3)
  - Appropriations Process 1982 (Box 3)
  - Chamber of Commerce 1982 (Box 3)
  - Chesapeake and its Tributaries 1982 (Box 3)
  - Chesapeake Bay 1982 (Box 3)
  - Chesterfield Board 1982 (Box 3)
  - Chesterfield Redistricting 1982 (Box 3)
  - Colonial Heights Information 1982 (Box 3)
  - Corrections 1982 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence 1982, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence-Elected Officials 1982 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence-Legislators 1982 (Box 3)
  - Counties, Cities and Towns Committee 1982, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Counties, Va Association of 1982 (Box 3)
  - Courts 1982 (Box 3)
  - Crater Planning District Commission 1982 (Box 3)
  - Cumulative Index 1982 (Box 3)
  - Drunk Driving SB 144 1982 (Box 3)
  - Education 1982 (Box 3)
  - Electric Power System 1982 (Box 3)
  - Employee Relations Counselors Annual Report 1982 (Box 3)
  - Employees-State and Federal 1982 (Box 3)
  - Energy Commission-Coal, Gas, Oil, etc. 1982 (Box 3)
  - Estate and Gift Tax 1982 (Box 3)
  - Family Life Education 1982 (Box 4)
  - Farm Bureau Annual Reports 1982 (Box 4)
  - Final Gas Tax Bill Passed HB 532 1982 (Box 4)
  - Fluoridation 1982, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Forest Industries 1982 (Box 4)
  - Game Warden 1982 (Box 4)
  - Gas and Oil Drilling SB 253 1982 (Box 4)
  - Gasoline Tax HB 532 1982 (Box 4)
  - Gasoline Retailers 1982 (Box 4)
  - General Assembly Summary 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Gun Control 1982 (Box 4)
  - Hampton Roads Annual Report 1982 (Box 4)
  - Handicapped 1982 (Box 4)
  - Hazardous Waste 1982 (Box 4)
  - Highway Department 1982 (Box 4)
  - Highways 1982 (Box 4)
  - Highways 1982 (Box 4)
  - Industrial Development (Virginia Division) 1982 (Box 4)
  - J. Sargeant Reynolds Master Plan 1982 (Box 4)
  - James River Corridor Study 1982 (Box 4)
  - Labor and Commerce Committee 1982, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Legislation not introduced 1982 (Box 4)
  - Legislative Aide Applications 1982 (Box 4)
  - Lobbyists 1982 (Box 4)
  - MEDICAD/Welfare/Soc. Sec. 1982 (Box 4)
  - Maps and Precinct Lines for Chesterfield, Powhatan and Colonial Heights 1982 (Box 4)
  - Va. Municipal League 1982 (Box 5)
  - National Republican Legislators Association 1982 (Box 5)
  - Occupational Therapy HB 823 1982 (Box 4)
  - Page Applications 1982 (Box 5)
  - Pamphlets 1982 (Box 5)
  - Plan 2000 1982 (Box 5)
  - Powhatan 1982 (Box 5)
  - Press Releases-General Assembly 1982 (Box 5)
  - Prompt Pay 1982 (Box 5)
  - Questionnaires 1982, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Redistrict/State 1982 (Box 5)
  - Registration Bill HB 604 1982 (Box 5)
  - Rehabilitative Services and Retarded Citizens 1982 (Box 5)
  - Republican Causes 1982 (Box 5)
  - Senate Procurement Legislation SB 96 1982 (Box 5)
  - State Water Control Board 1982 (Box 5)
  - Taxation 1982 (Box 5)
  - Transportation 1982 (Box 5)
  - Trible, Paul 1982 (Box 5)
  - Uranium 1982 (Box 5)
  - VA Education Association 1982 (Box 5)
  - VA Historical Landmarks Commission 1982 (Box 5)
  - VA League of Planned Parenthood, Inc. 1982 (Box 5)
  - VEC (Labor and Commerce) 1982 (Box 5)
  - Veto Session 1982 (Box 5)
  - Virginia Boards and Commissions 1982 (Box 5)
  - Virginia Department Alcoholic Beverage Control 1982 (Box 5)
  - Virginia Employment Commission 1982 (Box 5)
  - Virginia Employment Commission Annual Report 1982 (Box 5)
  - Virginia Government 1982 (Box 5)
  - Virginia Health Services Cost Review Commission and Report 1982 (Box 5)
  - Water Information 1982 (Box 5)
  - Aging, Agency on 1983 (Box 6)
  - Aging, Agency on 1983 (Box 6)
  - Agriculture 1983 (Box 6)
  - Alcoholic Stores-ABC 1983 (Box 6)
  - Block Grants 1983 (Box 6)
  - Budget 1983 (Box 6)
  - Chamber of Commerce 1983 (Box 6)
  - Chambers of Commerce/Chesterfield Business Council 1983 (Box 6)
  - Chesapeake Bay Study 1983 (Box 6)
  - Chesterfield County 1983, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Chesterfield County Airport 1983 (Box 6)
  - Chesterfield County Legislation 1983 (Box 6)
  - Chesterfield School Board 1983 (Box 6)
  - Child Restraint Statistics 1983 (Box 6)
  - Code Commission 1983 (Box 6)
  - Committee Assignments, Meetings (1983 House/Senate) 1983 (Box 6)
  - Common Cause 1983 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence 1983 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Constituents 1983 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence wit Leaders and Elected Officials 1983 (Box 6)
  - Counties, Cities and Towns Committee 1983 (Box 6)
  - Crime 1983 (Box 6)
  - Crime Including Jails 1983 (Box 6)
  - Deposit-Containers Bill 1983 (Box 6)
  - Education 1983 (Box 7)
  - Employment and/or Training 1983 (Box 7)
  - Energy 1983 (Box 7)
  - Ethics SB 23 1983 (Box 7)
  - Gasoline Retailers 1983 (Box 7)
  - General Assembly 1983 (Box 7)
  - General Correspondence 1983, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Governor Charles Robb 1983 (Box 7)
  - Handicapped 1983 (Box 7)
  - Highways 1983 (Box 7)
  - Hospital and Health Care 1983 (Box 7)
  - House Committee on Agriculture 1983 (Box 7)
  - Human Resources 1983 (Box 7)
  - Input on Legislature Requested 1983 (Box 7)
  - Industrial Commission 1983 (Box 7)
  - Insurance 1983 (Box 7)
  - Joint Subcommittee/Unemployment Compensation Trust Fund 1983 (Box 7)
  - Judgeship 1983 (Box 7)
  - Judicial Council 1983 (Box 7)
  - Labor and Commerce Committee 1983 (Box 7)
  - Landscape Architects 1983 (Box 7)
  - Law Enforcement 1983 (Box 7)
  - Legislative Aide Applications 1983 (Box 7)
  - Letters from School Children 1983 (Box 7)
  - Literary Fund 1983 (Box 7)
  - Lobbyists 1983 (Box 7)
  - Lobbyists Registered with the Secretary of the Commonwealth 1983 (Box 7)
  - Lottery, State 1983 (Box 7)
  - Manhole Study Bill 1983 (Box 8)
  - Maritime and Water Information 1983 (Box 8)
  - Murray, Richard 1977-1983 (Box 8)
  - Natural Death Act HB 329 1983 (Box 8)
  - NAACP/SCLC and Martin King Bill 1983 (Box 8)
  - News Clippings, etc. 1983 (Box 8)
  - Newspaper Advertising Tax HB 669 1983 (Box 8)
  - Nuclear Weapons Freeze 1983 (Box 8)
  - Optometry and Drug Legislation 1983 (Box 8)
  - Perinatal 1983 (Box 8)
  - Postage 1983 (Box 8)
  - Professional Regulations 1983 (Box 8)
  - Questionnaires 1983 (Box 8)
  - Resolutions SJR 67 1983 (Box 8)
  - Recreations 1983 (Box 8)
  - Robb, Charles S. (Governor) 1983 (Box 8)
  - Social Services 1983 (Box 8)
  - Republican Caucus 1983 (Box 8)
  - Retirement System-Annual Report 1981 (Box 8)
  - Retirement 1983 (Box 8)
  - Richmond, City of 1983 (Box 8)
  - Richmond-Petersburg Turnpike Table 1983 (Box 8)
  - State Colleges and Universities 1983 (Box 8)
  - Subdivision Ordinance 1983 (Box 8)
  - Tax Exemptions 1983 (Box 8)
  - Tax Gasoline 1983 (Box 8)
  - Toll Road 1983 (Box 8)
  - Twin Trailers 1983 (Box 8)
  - Unclaimed Property 1983 (Box 8)
  - Unemployment 1983 (Box 8)
  - Uranium Mining and Milling 1983 (Box 8)
  - Validation Date HB 806 1983 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Bankers' Association 1983 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Correctional Facilities 1983 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Government 1983 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Municipal League 1983 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Water Project 1983 (Box 8)
  - Wait Week 1983 (Box 8)
  - Waste Week 1983 (Box 8)
  - Water 1983 (Box 8)
  - Watkins, John 1983 (Box 8)
  - Wine Study 1983 (Box 8)
  - Workmen's Compensation 1983 (Box 8)
  - Abortion 1984 (Box 9)
  - Alcoholics Beverage Control 1984 (Box 9)
  - Appreciation Letters of 1984 (Box 9)
  - Agriculture 1984 (Box 9)
  - Arts in Virginia 1984 (Box 9)
  - Banking 1984 (Box 9)
  - Bills in Conference 1984 (Box 9)
  - Bottle Bill 1984 (Box 9)
  - Bow Hunters 1984 (Box 9)
  - Budget Matters 1984 (Box 9)
  - Campaign (statewide) 1984 (Box 9)
  - Chesapeake Bay and Tributaries 1984, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Civic Leagues 1984 (Box 9)
  - Clippings 1984 (Box 9)
  - Coal Slurry-Constituents Letters 1984 (Box 9)
  - Coal Slurry-Constituents Letters #2 1984 (Box 9)
  - Coal Slurry-General Information 1984 (Box 9)
  - Coal Slurry-Press Release and News Clippings 1984 (Box 9)
  - Construction/Contractors 1984 (Box 9)
  - Consumer 1989 (Box 9)
  - Contributory and Comparative Negligence 1984 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence 1984, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Courts and Virginia Bars 1984 (Box 9)
  - Dental 1984 (Box 9)
  - Disabled and handicapped 1984 (Box 9)
  - Drugs and Alcohol 1984 (Box 9)
  - Drunk Driving 1984, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Education-Chesterfield County 1984 (Box 9)
  - Education General Correspondence 1984 (Box 9)
  - Education-General Information 1984 (Box 9)
  - Education-News Clippings 1984 (Box 9)
  - Education-VEA 1984 (Box 10)
  - Embryo Transplant 1984 (Box 10)
  - Energy 1984 (Box 10)
  - Federal Election Commission 1984 (Box 10)
  - Fire 1984 (Box 10)
  - Fire Protection-Multi Story Structure 1984 (Box 10)
  - Flow Control 1984 (Box 10)
  - Forest Products 1984 (Box 10)
  - Form Letters 1984 (Box 10)
  - Gas Pipeline 1984 (Box 10)
  - General Newspaper Clippings 1984, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Genetics/Life Science Research 1984 (Box 10)
  - Government, Local 1984 (Box 10)
  - Governor Robb 1984 (Box 10)
  - Health Including Insurance 1984 (Box 10)
  - Highway and Roads 1984 (Box 10)
  - History 1984 (Box 10)
  - Hospital and Health Care 1984 (Box 10)
  - House Bills 164, 165, 693 Senate Bills 90, 91, 292 1984, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - House of Delegates 1984 Session (Mine Journal) 1984 (Box 10)
  - Impact Statements 1984 (Box 10)
  - Independent Businesses 1984 (Box 10)
  - Insurance 1984 (Box 10)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (Equity for Allocating Highway Funds) 1984 (Box 10)
  - Juvenile Matters including Day Care Centers and Jails 1984 (Box 10)
  - King, Martin Luther 1984 (Box 10)
  - Labor 1984 (Box 10)
  - Legal Service and Real Estate 1984 (Box 10)
  - Lottery and Gambling 1984 (Box 10)
  - Manufacturers/Retailers Association 1984 (Box 10)
  - Mecklenburg Report 1984 (Box 10)
  - Minority Leader's Report 1984 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous 1984 (Box 10)
  - Official Spokesman to Members of the General Assembly 1984 (Box 10)
  - OSHA 1984 (Box 10)
  - News Letters 1984 (Box 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1984 (Box 10)
  - NOVA Planning District Commission 1984 (Box 10)
  - Pharmacy 1984 (Box 11)
  - Patron Reports 1984 (Box 11)
  - Political Action Money 1984 (Box 11)
  - Pollution, Waste, Litter 1984 (Box 11)
  - Population 1984 (Box 11)
  - Powhatan County 1984 (Box 11)
  - Postage 1984 (Box 11)
  - Prompt Pay 1984 (Box 11)
  - Republican 1984 (Box 11)
  - Republicans 1984 (Box 11)
  - Resolutions 1984 (Box 11)
  - Science and Technology 1984 (Box 11)
  - Social Welfare 1984 (Box 11)
  - Surveyors 1984 (Box 11)
  - TV 1984 (Box 11)
  - Tax Payers 1984 (Box 11)
  - Taxes 1984 (Box 11)
  - Transportation 1984 (Box 11)
  - Uranium Subcommittee 1984, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Utilities 1984 (Box 11)
  - Virginia Association of Counties 1984 (Box 11)
  - Virginia Government Reorganization and Critical Re-evaluation 1984 (Box 11)
  - Virginia Nurseryman 1984 (Box 11)
  - Virginia Retail Merchants Association 1984 (Box 11)
  - Virginia Supplemental Retirement System 1984 (Box 11)
  - Veterans 1984 (Box 11)
  - Voter Registration 1984 (Box 11)
  - Voter Surveys 1984 (Box 11)
  - Voting 1984 (Box 11)
  - Water/Waste Water 1984 (Box 11)
  - Wine 1984 (Box 11)
  - Women's Organization 1984 (Box 11)
  - Abortion 1985 (Box 12)
  - Altavista-House Bill 99 1985 (Box 12)
  - Aging Commission 1985 (Box 12)
  - Appreciation-Letter of 1984 (Box 12)
  - Agribusiness 1985 (Box 12)
  - Agriculture 1985 (Box 12)
  - Agriculture-Farm Bureau 1985 (Box 12)
  - Budget 1985 (Box 12)
  - Boy Scouts Resolution 1985 (Box 12)
  - Chesterfield County Legislation 1985 (Box 12)
  - Chesterfield-Positions on Legislation 1985 (Box 12)
  - Chesterfield-School Board 1985 (Box 12)
  - Chichester (campaign) 1985 (Box 12)
  - Child Abuse/Safety 1985 (Box 12)
  - Coal Energy Commission 1985 (Box 12)
  - Coal Slurry 1985 (Box 12)
  - Committee Assignments-House 1985 (Box 12)
  - Committee-Natural Resources 1985 (Box 12)
  - Conservation 1985 (Box 12)
  - Construction-Contractors 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Abortion/Church, School 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Advertising Tax 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Coal Slurry 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Elected Officials 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence 1985, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Correspondence/General 1985, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Marie/GOP 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Group House 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Leaders 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Legislators 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-No Response 1984 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-SB 643 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-School Board/Kinder 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Seatbelts 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-SJR 28 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Uranium 1985 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence-Utility/SCC 1985 (Box 12)
  - Counties/Cities/Towns 1985, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Courts 1985 (Box 12)
  - Credit Card 1985 (Box 12)
  - CSE Issue Analysis 1985 (Box 12)
  - Department Heads 1985 (Box 13)
  - Department of Health 1985 (Box 13)
  - Economic 1985 (Box 13)
  - Education 1985 (Box 13)
  - Employment Commission 1985 (Box 13)
  - Energy 1985 (Box 13)
  - Equine Center 1985 (Box 13)
  - ERA Human Rights Act 1985 (Box 13)
  - First Choice Chesterfield, VA 1985 (Box 13)
  - Forestry 1985 (Box 13)
  - Garcia Decision 1985 (Box 13)
  - Government Employees 1985 (Box 13)
  - Gubernatorial Terms 1985 (Box 13)
  - Handicapped 1985 (Box 13)
  - Holidays 1985 (Box 13)
  - HUD 1985 (Box 13)
  - Hunger 1985 (Box 13)
  - Insurance 1985 (Box 13)
  - Issues Groups/Durette 1985 (Box 13)
  - JLARC 1985 (Box 13)
  - Joint Subcommittee/Election Laws 1985 (Box 13)
  - Judges 1985 (Box 13)
  - Juvenile-Day Care 1985 (Box 13)
  - Labor 1985 (Box 13)
  - Land Subdivision and Development 1985 (Box 13)
  - Landscape/Tenant Act 1985 (Box 13)
  - Legislators' G.A. Reports 1985 (Box 13)
  - Lobbyists 1985 (Box 13)
  - Lottery 1985 (Box 13)
  - Magnolia Grange-Budget Amendment 1985 (Box 13)
  - Manufactured Housing 1985 (Box 13)
  - Mary Washington College Name Change Request 1985 (Box 13)
  - Metro Chamber 1985 (Box 13)
  - Minority Leader Reports 1985 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous News Clippings 1985 (Box 13)
  - Natural Federation of Independent Businesses 1985 (Box 13)
  - Natural Guard 1985 (Box 13)
  - News Clippings, etc. 1985, 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Parimutuel Betting 1985 (Box 14)
  - Pollution 1985 (Box 14)
  - Preservation Alliance 1985 (Box 14)
  - Privileges and Elections 1985, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Privileges and Elections Committee 1985 (Box 14)
  - Prompt Pay 1985 (Box 14)
  - Real Estate 1985 (Box 14)
  - Resources Authority 1985 (Box 14)
  - Republican Convention 1985 (Box 14)
  - Republican Party 1985 (Box 14)
  - Retail Merchants Association 1985 (Box 14)
  - Richmond Regional Planning District 1985 (Box 14)
  - Richmond-Petersburg Turnpike 1985 (Box 14)
  - SPCA Animals 1985 (Box 14)
  - Schedule 1985 (Box 14)
  - School Boards 1985 (Box 14)
  - Seatbelts 1985 (Box 14)
  - Secretary of Natural Resources 1985 (Box 14)
  - Silver Haired Legislation 1985 (Box 14)
  - Spas 1985 (Box 14)
  - State Colleges and Universities 1985 (Box 14)
  - State Employees SB 643 1985 (Box 14)
  - TV 1985 (Box 14)
  - Tax Exemptions 1985 (Box 14)
  - Taxes 1985 (Box 14)
  - Telephone 1985 (Box 14)
  - Tobacco/Smoking 1985 (Box 14)
  - Trucks/Trucking 1985 (Box 14)
  - Unemployment 1985 (Box 14)
  - Uranium 1985 (Box 14)
  - Utilities 1985 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Aeronautics 1985 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Association of Community Service 1985 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Chamber of Commerce 1985 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Government 1985 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Education Association 1985 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Hospital Association 1985 (Box 14)
  - Veterans 1985 (Box 14)
  - Water 1985 (Box 14)
  - Wine 1985 (Box 14)
  - Women's Organizations 1985 (Box 14)
  - Abortion 1986 (Box 15)
  - Abortion-Correspondence 1986 (Box 15)
  - Agribusiness 1986 (Box 15)
  - Agriculture HB 208, etc. 1986 (Box 15)
  - Agriculture Farm Bureau 1986 (Box 15)
  - Assignments 1986 (Box 15)
  - Building Code Amendment HB 311 1986 (Box 15)
  - Budget Amendments 1986 (Box 15)
  - Bottle Bill 1986 (Box 15)
  - Bottle Bill-Correspondence 1986 (Box 15)
  - CADRE 1986 (Box 15)
  - Campaign 1986 (Box 15)
  - Chesterfield County 1986 (Box 15)
  - Chesterfield County 1985-1986 (Box 15)
  - Chesterfield Legislation 1986 (Box 15)
  - Chief Pardon Report 1986 (Box 15)
  - Child Care Regulations 1986 (Box 15)
  - Children 1986 (Box 15)
  - Chron. Copies 1986, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Cigarette Sales Below Wholesale 1986 (Box 15)
  - Clerk 1986 (Box 15)
  - Coal and Energy Commission 1986 (Box 15)
  - Concerned Parents Association 1986 (Box 15)
  - Conflict of Interest HB 580 1986 (Box 15)
  - Conservation 1986 (Box 15)
  - Co-Patron Bills 1986 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence-Chesterfield 1986 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence 1986, 5 folders (Box 15)
  - Correspondence-General 1986, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Correspondence-Legislators 1986 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence-No Response 1986 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence-Uranium 1986 (Box 16)
  - Council on the Environment 1986 (Box 16)
  - Counties, Cities and Towns 1986 (Box 16)
  - CPA Bill 1986 (Box 16)
  - Deli Bill 1986 (Box 16)
  - Dieticians and Nutricionists HJR 150 1986 (Box 16)
  - Drunk Driving HB 502 1986 (Box 16)
  - Education 1986 (Box 16)
  - Education Assistance Authority 1986 (Box 16)
  - Election Laws Sub-Committee 1986 (Box 16)
  - ERA-Youth 1986 (Box 16)
  - Ethanol/Alcohol 1986 (Box 16)
  - Farm Security Interest 1986 (Box 16)
  - Federal Judgeships 1986 (Box 16)
  - Gas Tax Bill 1986 (Box 16)
  - Gifted and Talented 1986 (Box 16)
  - GOP Caucus 1986 (Box 16)
  - Governor 1986 (Box 16)
  - Gramm/Rudman/Hollings 1986 (Box 16)
  - Group Homes 1986 (Box 16)
  - Health 1986 (Box 16)
  - Higher Education 1986 (Box 16)
  - Highways and Transportation 1986 (Box 16)
  - Historical Districts 1986 (Box 16)
  - Insurance Corporation 1986 (Box 16)
  - Issues, Other 1986 (Box 16)
  - Jail and Prison Overcrowding 1986 (Box 16)
  - Judgeship 1986 (Box 16)
  - Judicial Interviews 1986 (Box 16)
  - King and Queen County Landfill 1986 (Box 16)
  - Land Surveyors 1986 (Box 16)
  - Lavery, Dr. William E. 1986 (Box 16)
  - Legal Services Corporation 1986 (Box 16)
  - Legislative Tour 1986 (Box 16)
  - Liability Insurance 1986 (Box 16)
  - Libraries 1986 (Box 16)
  - License Revocation or Suspension HB 574 (ABC Law.Gay Bars) 1986 (Box 16)
  - Lottery 1986 (Box 16)
  - Lottery Correspondence 1986 (Box 16)
  - Magnolia Grange 1986 (Box 16)
  - Metro Chamber 1986 (Box 16)
  - Mental Health 1986 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous 1986, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - News Clippings 1986, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - News Releases 1986 (Box 16)
  - Optometrists 1986 (Box 17)
  - Nova Builders Association 1986 (Box 17)
  - Phosphate 1986 (Box 17)
  - Phosphate Ban 1986 (Box 17)
  - Powhatan Child Care 1986 (Box 17)
  - Privileges and Elections Committee 1986, 2 folders (Box 17)